Finding Aid for the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California Records LSC.0900
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Court Cases
  - Brief Filed in April 1954 in the United States Court of Appeals, San Francisco, by National ACLU and Northern California Affiliate (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Edward J. Lessin, et al, v. Regents of the University of California, et al. (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Leonard Saldana v. United States of America (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Florence M. Sloat v. Francis E. Walter, Morgan M. Moulder, August E. Johansen, and William Wheeler (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Board of Education School District of Pennsylvania v. Angelina Intille, Thomas Deacon, and Sadie T. Atkinson (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Freedom of Information Center Publication No. 77 - Canon 35: A Summary (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - William Goldman Theatres, Inc., and Pennsylvania Association of Amusement Industries v. Peter T. Dana, Mae M. Bergin, and Ira C. Sassaman - Statement of ACLU, Greater Philadelphia Branch (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Barbara Elfbrandt v. Imogene R. Russell, L.E. Bool, and Martha L. Elliot, et al. (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania ex rel. James Morris Fletcher v. Angelo C. Cavell (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - United States ex rel. Samuel Tito Williams v. J. Edwin Lavalle (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Edwin J. Del'Marmol v. Richard A. Chappell, Eva Bowring, Edward J. Donovan, John B. Henry, and George J. Reed (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Robert F. Kennedy v. Roscoe Quincy Proctor (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - United States of America v. William Schneiderman et al. (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - State of California Before the Fair Employment Practice Commission - Lennie J. Andrews (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - The New American Liberty of World Literature, Inc. v. Edward J. Allen (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Edward L. Schempp et al. v. School District of Albington Townships et al (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - The People of the State of California v. Phillip Book (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - United Artists Theatre Circuit Inc v. Wage Earners Committee of the United States of America, Inc. (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Bantam Books, Inc. v. Matthew F. Melko, 1953 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Levitt and Sons, Inc. and William J. Levitt v. Division Against Discrimination in the State Department of Education, Willie R. James, and Franklin D. Todd (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Kingsley International Pictures Corporation v. Victor Blanc (Box 94, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - Greater Kansas City ACLU (Box 95, Folder 19)
  - Louisiana ACLU (Box 95, Folder 22)
  - Pacific Citizen - June 28, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - NY Times - President John F. Kennedy (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Handbill Case - Manuel D. Talley (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Caryl Chessman (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Fulmer/Lindstrom Case (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Wein Case (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - Capital Punishment - Death Penalty (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - Driver's License Picture Dispute 1963 (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Textbook Loanings 1963 (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Red Ban Party (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - Obscenity Law - Pornography (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - Glenn Anderson (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - Peyote Case 1963 (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - Elizabeth Duncan Case, 1959-1961 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Censorship - Post Office 1959-63 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Freedom of Press 1963 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - "Mug Shots" Case (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Pacifica Probe (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Teachers Hearing 1959 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Un-American Committee sued (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - ACLU seeks abolition of Un- American Committee (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Miscellaneous Cases 1963 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Wheeldin v. Wheeler (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Sloat v. Simpson (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Wilkinson (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Globe and Nelson (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Cases - Gottlieb and Fordis (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - House Committee on Un-American ActivitiesCases - "Operation Abolition" (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Schools (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Loyalty Oaths - School use 1959-1963 (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Separation of Church and State - Religious Disputes 1962-1963 (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Narcotics (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - Pilgrimage Play and events (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Religious Disputes in Public Institutions, School Prayer Decision, and Pledge of Allegiance: Newspaper Clippings (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - LA Red Probe - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Chapters (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Attacks, Critics, Anti-ACLU, Pro-ACLU 1960-1963 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Lee Harvey Oswald 1963 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Arts Division 1962-1963 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Awards 1963 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Beard Dispute 1963 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Police 1964 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Masae Kondo - Yen Depositor 1964 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Helen Travis - Cuba 1964 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Communications Award Contest 1964 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - House Fair 1964 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Bill of Rights 1964 (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Tribute for Steve Allen 1964 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Events 1964 (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Obscenity - Censorship 1964 (Box 101, Folder 15)
  - Privacy 1964 (Box 101, Folder 16)
  - Republican Party (Box 101, Folder 17)
  - Civil Liberties 1964 (Box 101, Folder 18)
  - Max Rafferty, Thomas Braden 1964 (Box 101, Folder 19)
  - Rumford Fair Housing Act 1964 (Box 101, Folder 20)
  - Bill of Rights Banquet 1959 (Box 101, Folder 21)
  - Bill of Rights Banquet 1961 (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Bill of Rights Banquet 1963 (Box 101, Folder 23)
  - Border Patrol (Box 101, Folder 24)
  - Hollywood Blacklist 1960-1961 (Box 101, Folder 25)
  - Nightie Arrest Case - Dorothy Mackray 1963 (Box 101, Folder 26)
  - Recording Ban - John Nevens 1963 (Box 101, Folder 27)
  - Motion Picture Classification Policy 1963 (Box 101, Folder 28)
  - The Dictionary of American Slang 1963 (Box 101, Folder 29)
  - African Ballet February 1961 (Box 101, Folder 30)
  - Weekly People 1961-1963 (Box 101, Folder 31)
  - "Tropic of Cancer" (Box 101, Folder 32)
  - Censorship 1963-1964 (Box 101, Folder 33)
  - Loyalty oaths - Wilson v. LA Civil Service (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Loyalty oaths - Wirin v. Ostley (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - National & others - Otsuka - conscientious objectors (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Police practices (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Police practices - brutality & illegal search - York, Lucero, Johnson, Smith, Carol Lane (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Proposition 24 - Louis Francis Amendment (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Racial discrimination - housing, real estate, schools - Vargas case, Hutchinson, Don Wilson (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Censorship - students - Nazi - UCLA pamphlets, speake (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - American Legion (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Joel Dvorman - Orange County (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Free speech - John Birch Society (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Machinists - free speech - right to work (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Burns committee report (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Teaching bill of rights (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - A.L. Wirin (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Racial discrimination - gambling laws (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Teachers - Wendell Phillips, Florence Sloat, Wellbaum (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Right to travel - Cuba (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Censorship cases (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Pauling party (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Pauling case (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Pat Michaels - Elsinore conspiracy (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - L.A. curfew - Ramos case (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - State bar - Marshall case (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous legal cases (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Major Johns (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - Radio - TV law institute - April 16, 1960 (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Bombings - terrorist tactics (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Search & seizure - Todisco case (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - Ex-felon registration law - Abbott case (Box 112, Folder 19)
  - HUAC (Box 112, Folder 20)
  - Black Socio-economic Position -- Censorship. Obscene Literature., undated. (Box 628)
  - Evergreen Review -- Consumer Protection., 1966- 1969 (Box 629)
  - Crime, Organized -- Fifth Amendment., undated. (Box 630)
  - Criminal Law/Trends -- Draft., undated. (Box 631)
  - Capital Punishment -- Black Power/Separatism., undated. (Box 632)
  - Davis v. L.A. Free Press -- Mexican Americans, Migrant Workers., 1968 (Box 633)
  - Poverty Programs - - Right Wing Rebuttal, undated (Box 634)
  - Political. ACLU Attacks -- Prisoners' Rights., undated. (Box 635)
  - SDS -- Teachers' Strike L.A., 1966- 1970 (Box 636)
  - Supreme Court Justices -- Constitutional; and Fundamental Rights., undated. (Box 637)
  - Student Protest. Harvard -- Racism., undated. (Box 638)
  - Student Protest. S.F. -- Protest. Peoples' Parl. Berkeley. (Box 639)
- [Archive -, n.d.]
  - Censorhip material. (Box 69)
  - Status of LACC chapter. (Box 69)
  - San Gabriel Valley. (Box 69)
  - Church-state committee. (Box 69)
  - American Civil Liberties Union v. Bd. of Education of San Diego. (Box 69)
  - ACLU of southern California v. Bd. of Education of Los Angeles. (Box 69)
  - Bill and cases pending. (Box 69)
  - ACLU court decisions. (Box 69)
  - Machinists case. (Box 69)
  - Wendell Phillips. (Box 69)
  - A.L. Wirin court analysis. (Box 70)
  - Wirin's radio program. (Box 70)
  - Integration in L.A. city schools. (Box 70)
  - Women's committee education workshop. (Box 70)
  - Lawyers workshop dinners,., 1962 (Box 70)
  - National legislation. (Box 70)
  - House un-American committee. (Box 70)
  - Wiretapping. (Box 70)
  - Community relations conference. (Box 70)
  - Fair employment practice commission. (Box 70)
  - Police brutality. (Box 70)
  - Police practices committee,., 1962 (Box 71)
  - Francis amendment. (Box 71)
  - Governor's committee on constitutional rights. (Box 71)
  - Operation womanpower. (Box 71)
  - Income/expense statements. (Box 71)
  - Special fund raising. (Box 71)
  - Statements, receipts, etc., A-R. (Box 71)
  - S-Z. (Box 72)
  - Taxes,., 1962 (Box 72)
  - Financial report., 1961/62 (Box 72)
  - Financial report to national. (Box 72)
  - Insurance policies. (Box 72)
  - Bill of rights,., 1962 (Box 72)
  - Constitution & by-laws, national. (Box 72)
  - Membership/promotion,., 1962 (Box 72)
  - Ventura,., 1962 (Box 72)
  - Postal permits. (Box 72)
  - Receipts, miscellaneous. (Box 72)
  - Paid bills,., 1960 (Box 72)
  - Paid Bills, A-Z., 1961 (Box 72)
  - Multiple copies-Correspondence. (Box 73)
  - Telegrams. (Box 73)
  - Correspondence, A-Z., 1963 (Box 73)
  - Minutes & Agenda: Board of directors. (Box 73)
  - Annual meeting/goals & activities/calendar of events. (Box 73)
  - Board organization. (Box 73)
  - Report of counsel,., 1963 (Box 73)
  - Women's division. (Box 74)
  - Equal educational opportunity committee. (Box 74)
  - Women's division. (Box 74)
  - Lawyers division. (Box 74)
  - A.L. Wirin's notes. (Box 74)
  - Community relations. (Box 74)
  - A.L. Wirin's biography. (Box 74)
  - Chapter program. (Box 74)
  - Riverside chapter. (Box 74)
  - House un-American committee. (Box 75)
  - Legislative action. (Box 75)
  - Legal action. (Box 76)
  - Public relations. (Box 76)
  - Communications awards. (Box 76)
  - Integration-Los Angeles project. (Box 76)
  - Birmingham. (Box 76)
  - Police review boards-police brutality cases. (Box 76)
  - Haswell Parker case. (Box 76)
  - University of California, Riverside. (Box 76)
  - Police review board. (Box 76)
  - Lessin v. Bd. of Regents (Riverside students). (Box 77)
  - Dr. Irving Taylor case. (Box 77)
  - Constitutional Rights section. (Box 77)
  - Miscellaneous/Attorney General, state of California. (Box 77)
  - Narcotics. (Box 77)
  - Membership promotion/finance. (Box 77)
  - Special projects. (Box 77)
  - Bills, A-Z., 1963 (Box 78)
  - Scripts. (Box 79)
  - Attorneys/current membership lists. (Box 79)
  - Arts/correspondence. (Box 79)
  - Arts division,., 1962 (Box 79)
  - Arts/committee lists. (Box 79)
  - Arts/publicity. (Box 79)
  - Arts mailing lists/now members. (Box 79)
  - Arts division/agendas, minutes, reports. (Box 79)
  - Arts division/radio spots. (Box 79)
  - Arts division/prospects. (Box 79)
  - Arts division/mailings. (Box 79)
  - ACLU southern California/finance. (Box 80)
  - Board minutes-southern California. (Box 80)
  - Southern California by-laws of ACLU. (Box 80)
  - Teachers. (Box 81)
  - City commissioners, prominent women, movies. (Box 81)
  - General organizations. (Box 81)
  - National dinner, human relations, Dr. Cooley. (Box 81)
  - Executive committee lists in numerical order. (Box 81)
  - Jewish year-book lists. (Box 81)
  - Appeal letters signed by Isaac Pacht. (Box 81)
  - Appeal letters to preachers. (Box 81)
  - Appeal letters to lawyers signed by Isaac Pacht. (Box 81)
  - Letters signed by Melvyn Douglas. (Box 81)
  - Appeal letters to Friends of the American Way. (Box 81)
  - Northern California minutes. (Box 82)
  - National office minutes-., 1926-1929 (Box 83)
  - ., 1930/31 (Box 83)
  - ., 1942/43 (Box 83)
  - ., 1944/45 (Box 83)
  - ., 1946-1949 (Box 83)
  - WITHDRAWN. Contents added to box 80. (Box 84)
  - Nazi handbill distributors. (Box 85)
  - Federation for the repeal of the Levering act. (Box 85)
  - Interim committee. (Box 85)
  - Legal action committee. (Box 85)
  - Lawyers civil liberty group. (Box 85)
  - Monroe-Southern California [Biennial Conference]. (Box 85)
  - Large-public-meeting notices. (Box 85)
  - Civil liberties docket. (Box 85)
  - Constitution & history-bill of rights. (Box 85)
  - Yankwich. (Box 85)
  - Baldwin comment. (Box 85)
  - Opinions on ACLU. (Box 85)
  - Fact book of the American Civil Liberties Union. (Box 85)
  - Bill of rights. (Box 86)
  - Pamphlets-ACLU. (Box 86)
  - ACLU counsel. (Box 86)
  - Branch structure. (Box 86)
  - Special fund raising. (Box 86)
  - Promotion. (Box 86)
  - School houses/civic centers. (Box 86)
  - Anti-subversive laws. (Box 86)
  - School boards. (Box 86)
  - Loyalty oath-state. (Box 86)
  - C.S.O. (Box 86)
  - National security committee. (Box 86)
  - Radio committee. (Box 86)
  - New York office-., 1946 (Box 86)
  - ACLU-tax problem. (Box 86)
  - County ordinances. (Box 87)
  - 25th anniversary. (Box 87)
  - Hollywood ten. (Box 87)
  - LACC. (Box 87)
  - County loyalty check. (Box 87)
  - Inter-branch correspondence-., 1949 (Box 87)
  - The 1959 investigation of California teachers by the HUAC. (Box 87)
  - New York office correspondence-., 1947 (Box 87)
  - Race relations & minority rights commissions. (Box 87)
  - City affairs. (Box 87)
  - International-Baldwin. (Box 87)
  - Governor Earl Warren. (Box 87)
  - Supreme court-recent decisions. (Box 87)
  - Supreme court-future cases. (Box 87)
  - Harry Slochower case. (Box 87)
  - Supreme court-William Ullman. (Box 87)
  - Supreme court-general. (Box 87)
  - How goes today?. (Box 87)
  - Coast guard case. (Box 87)
  - American Indians. (Box 87)
  - ACLU-facts & annual report. (Box 87)
  - Reply to Legion article. (Box 87)
  - Arthur Garfield Hays. (Box 87)
  - Current supreme court cases. (Box 87)
  - History-ACLU. (Box 88)
  - National defense education act. (Box 88)
  - Linus Pauling hearing. (Box 88)
  - Supreme court attempts to curb. (Box 88)
  - Powell Schumann case-sedition. (Box 88)
  - Right to work. (Box 88)
  - Segregation-sports. (Box 88)
  - Seltz case. (Box 88)
  - Sit-in movement. (Box 88)
  - Tax statements, federal & state., 1958/59 - (Box 88)
  - Executive committee minutes. (Box 88)
  - Morton Sobell. (Box 88)
  - State anti-discrimination agencies. (Box 88)
  - Student civil liberties. (Box 88)
  - Sudent demonstration-., May 13 (Box 88)
  - Segregation-schools. (Box 88)
  - Rodney Clare. (Box 89)
  - Security & Secrecy. (Box 89)
  - Academic freedom. (Box 89)
  - New York office-., 1950 (Box 89)
  - Civil liberties-October,., 1952-December, 1955 (Box 89)
  - Fifth amendment. (Box 89)
  - Financial records of ACLU. (Box 90)
  - Invoices. (Box 91)
  - Protests of school books. (Box 91)
  - Biennial conference-., June, 1964 (Box 91)
  - Correspondence:., 1940-1964 (Box 92)
  - Memoranda:., 1937-1961 (Box 93)
  - Memoranda:., 1962-1964 (Box 94)
  - National organ minutes:., 1951-1964 (Box 95)
  - Press releases:., 1954-1964 (Box 96)
  - Unsorted publications (ACLU only) Various pamphlets; ACLU Annual Reports, 34-37, 39-43., (1951-) (Box 97)
  - Unsorted publications: books, mimeographed reports, pamphlets. (Box 98)
  - Unsorted publications: journals, state reports, hearing transcripts. (Box 99)
  - Congressional hearings. (Box 100)
  - Unsorted legal documents. (Box 101)
  - Scrapbooks of newspaper clippings dealing primarily with the detention of Japanese-Americans in California. (Box 754, Box 755)
  - Three maps., The first deals with California political subdivisions. The second deals with the census divisions of all the counties in California. The third and last map deals with the census tracts of Los Angeles county. (Box 756)
- Archive, 1963-1965
  General note
  No index has been prepared for these years. The alphabetical arrangement of the files easily facilitates the location of desired materials.
  - Academic Freedom Committee (Southern California & National). (Box 114)
  - Anti-Poverty Program. (Box 114)
  - Arts Division. (Box 114)
  - ACLU Awards. (Box 114)
  - Bail. (Box 114)
  - Biennial Conference - Summary. (Box 114)
  - Board of Directors - Correspondence., 1963-1965 (Box 114)
  - Election of Board Members results -., 1965 (Box 114)
  - Minutes., 1963-1965 (Box 114)
  - Nominating Committee., 1964 (Box 114)
  - Notices., 1963-1965 (Box 114)
  - Staff Meetings., 1964-1965 (Box 114)
  - Californias Against Proposition 14 (CAP 14) (Box 115)
    See also box 129.
    - - Housing Initiative. (Box 115)
    - - Vigilance Fund Grant Memo. (Box 115)
  - California Committee for Fair Practices. (Box 115)
  - Capital Punishment Committee. (Box 115)
  - Censorship Committee (Southern California & National). (Box 115)
  - Chapter Correspondence. (Box 115)
  - Chapter Notices. (Box 115)
  - Church-State Relations Committee (So. California & National). (Box 115)
  - Church-State Committee (National) - Working papers and position statements., 1963-1965 (Box 116)
  - Church-State Relations. (Box 116)
  - Civil Disobedience (National). (Box 116)
  - Civil Liberties - Berkeley. (Box 116)
  - - Fifth Amendment. (Box 116)
  - Civil Rights Bill. (Box 116)
  - Civil Rights Committee. (Box 116)
  - Civil Rights - Court Decisions. (Box 116)
  - Law Enforcement. (Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins/Misc. Organizations. (Box 116)
  - Negro Actors for Action (Don Marshall). (Box 116)
  - Tapes. (Box 116)
  - United Civil Rights Committee (UCRC). (Box 116)
  - Community Relations Conference of So. California. (Box 117)
  - Conferences - Annual Conference/ Leadership Conference., 1964 1965 (Box 117)
  - Conscription. (Box 117)
  - Constitutional Amendment - Reapportionment (Box 117)
    [See also Box 124]
  - Counsel Reports. (Box 117)
  - Cray Reports. (Box 117)
  - Correspondence - Eason Monroe. (Box 118)
  - Correspondence - Carolyn Bloomberg. (Box 119)
  - - Laurence R. Sperber. (Box 119)
  - - Miscellaneous. (Box 119)
  - - To or About ACLU. (Box 119)
  - Debate - Material for National Collegiate Debate, (National)., 1965 (Box 120)
  - Due Process Committee - Minutes. (Box 120)
  - Education Committee. (Box 120)
  - Education - Federal Aid to... (Shared time, etc.). (Box 120)
  - Equality Committee - Minutes, Working Papers, and Statements. (Box 120)
  - Executive Committee Minutes. (Box 120)
  - Free Speech and Association Committee (Southern California & National). (Box 120)
  - Free Speech - and Press. (Box 120)
  - - Due Process - Working Papers and Position Statement. (Box 120)
  - - Movement - Bulletins. (Box 120)
  - - Berkeley Folder on Berkeley. (Box 120)
  - Fair Employment Practice Commission. (Box 120)
  - Michael Hannon case. (Box 121)
  - Housing - Good Neighbors of Southern California, Inc. (Box 121)
  - KNXT Editorials. (Box 121)
  - Labor - Business Committee. (Box 121)
  - Labor - Fair Employment Committee. (Box 121)
  - Law Enforcement. (Box 121)
  - Lawyers Constitutional Defense Committee of ACLU, Inc. (LCDC). (Box 121)
  - Lawyers Division -., 1964 (Box 121)
  - ., - 1965 (Box 121)
  - Legal Action Committee -., 1964-1965 (Box 122)
  - Legal Docket. (Box 122)
  - Legal Opinions/Attorney General. (Box 122)
  - Legislative Advocate Correspondence - Coleman Blease. (Box 122)
  - Legislative Campaigns of the Future. (Box 122)
  - Legislative Committe -., 1964 (Box 122)
  - - Bulletins -., 1964-1965 (Box 122)
  - Legislative Conferences. (Box 122)
  - Legislative Investigations and/or Hearings. (Box 122)
  - Legislative Procedures (Southern California). (Box 122)
  - Legislative Reports - Coleman Blease. (Box 122)
  - - Lawrence Speiser (National). (Box 122)
  - Legislators - Correspondence to and from. (Box 122)
  - Loyalty Oaths. (Box 122)
  - Archive, 1966
    These records were deposited in January, 1968. Although most of the files cover the year 1966, earlier and later materials are included.
    The following listing of the files is generally in alphabetical order. Consequently, no index has been prepared.
    - Academic Freedom Committee - Minutes -., 1966 (Box 126)
    - Abortions (Working Papers) Zarky, Epstein, Paul. (Box 126)
    - Academic Freedom - Complaints in High school and Junior Colleges. (Box 126)
    - Arrest - If you are arrested. (Box 126)
    - Arts division. (Box 126)
    - ACLU Communication Award. (Box 126)
    - Arrest and/or conviction records and government hiring. (Box 126)
    - Beverly Hills Answering Service Ordinance. (Box 126)
    - Bill of Rights - Dinner -., 1966 (Box 126)
    - Board of Directors (Box 126)
      - - Minutes -., 1966 (Box 126)
      - - Correspondence. (Box 126)
      - - Notices -., 1966 (Box 126)
      - - Executive Committee -., 1966 (Box 126)
      - - Nominating Committee -., 1966 (Box 126)
      - - Proposed Program - Goals., 1966 (Box 126)
      - - 1940 Resolution/ Caughey Proposal. (Box 126)
    - Capital Punishment - Execution dates. (Box 127)
    - Capital Punishment Committee -., 1966 (Box 127)
    - Censorship Committee -., 1966 (Box 127)
    - Bullock reprint - Employment and Training (empty). (Box 127)
    - Censorship - Obscenity - Librarians statement and others. (Box 127)
    - Chapter correspondence. (Box 127)
    - Chapter notices and bulletins. (Box 127)
    - Cesar Chavez - Migratory workers. (Box 127)
    - Church-State Relations Committee. (Box 127)
    - Civil liberties docket. (Box 127)
    - Community Relations Conference of Southern California -., 1966 (Box 127)
    - Commission on Human Relations - Los Angeles county. (Box 127)
    - Conference - Students -., March 19, 1966 (Box 127)
    - C.A.P. 14 Campaign [Californians Against Propostition 14]., 1964 (Box 127)
    - Correspondence: Carolyn Bloomberg, Executive Secretary -., 1966. (Box 128)
    - General correspondence. (Box 128)
    - Eason Monroe, Executive Director. (Box 128)
    - Correspondence: Laurence R. Sperber, Assistant Counsel (Box 129)
      - - Live correspondence -., 1966 (Box 129)
      - - Final correspondence -., 1966 (Box 129)
      - - Correspondence - Regrets A - U. (Box 130)
      - - Correspondence - Regrets V - Z. (Box 131)
      - A - L., July - Dec. 1966 (Box 131)
      - M - Z., July - Dec. 1966 - (Box 132)
      - A - F., Regrets - 1967 (Box 132)
      - Regrets - G - Z., 1967 (Box 133)